253 Beckhampton Road, Nottingham, NG5 5NE elliot@elliotjreed.com +44 (0) 7708 309156

www.elliotjreed.com github.com/elliotjreed

# Summary

Technical Lead with over nine years software development and management experience primarily using *PHP*, *Symfony*, *Javascript*, *React*, and *SQL* on *Linux*, *Docker*, *continuous integration* platforms, *Ansible*, *Git*, and *AWS*. Leading, training, and mentoring developers with a focus on test-driven development and clean code practices.

## **Employment**

#### **Technical Lead**

Bunches, 2017 to Present

Responsible for designing, developing, and maintaining websites and internal systems; and training and mentoring developers.

- Introduced a wide range of logging, analytics, and A/B testing tools, reducing errors to near 0% and providing data on design and feature effects on overall conversion;
- Changed payment providers to Braintree and Stripe saving ~30% on transaction fees;
- Migrated from traditional server architecture to automated container-based builds via Continuous Integration, resulting in a ~70% cost saving;
- Implemented a fraud detection system, resulting in a 98% reduction in fraudulent activity;
- Refactored and segregated internal systems, upgrading from PHP 5.6 on a custom backend to PHP 7.0 (now 8.1) on Symfony, and upgraded the primary website from Symfony 2.3 to Symfony 6.1 and React 18 resulting in a significant increase in development velocity and user experience;
- Developed product personalisation in React for user-uploaded photographs, with moderation via AWS Rekognition, and inhouse printing;
- Migrated two large separate databases with 25 years of data into one normalised AWS RDS database resulting in a significant reduction in manual data processing and cost;
- Implemented a stock system to facilitate lean practices for perishable fast-moving "in-house" manufactured products.

## Programming

- PHP (5.4 8.1)
- Symfony
- Javascript
- React (16 18)
- MySQL, Postgres
- SQLite
- CSS, SASS, LESS
- Bash / Shell
- Some Python
- A little Go

# Systems & DevOps

- Git
- GitHub Actions
- Ansible
- Docker
- Vagrant
- RabbitMQ
- Redis
- Linux
- NginX
- Apache
- Cloudflare
- DigitalOcean
- Elasticsearch
- AWS RDS
- AWS SQS
- AWS EC2
- AWS Rekognition

## **Software Development Manager**

Universal Textiles, 2015 to 2017

Responsible for a team of developers integrating third-party partners and platforms active in over 30 countries and 8 languages.

- Migrated legacy code to objectoriented design on the Slim framework;
- Implemented a Scrum-based approach to workload management;
- Optimised warehouse operations through the implementation of a fluid stock system to reduce average "pick" time by over 20%;
- Developed an automated product listing system, halving image content management time;
- Visited and hosted prospective clients to discuss current and potential integrations, obtaining and onboarding several new partners.

## **E-Commerce & IT Manager (Director)**

Polyverse Ltd, 2012 to 2015

Responsible for e-commerce operations and software development.

- Designed and implemented Magento websites and internal systems in PHP, Python, MySQL, and Javascript;
- Managed Google and Facebook PPC advertising, and multi-channel content on eBay and Amazon;
- Implemented a digital pick, pack, and dispatch process to reduce order errors to under 1%;
- Managed customer service, warehouse, and administrative teams, budgets, and suppliers;
- Managed alternative projects in bricksand-mortar retail and hospitality.

### Education

## **Graduate Diploma in Law**

Nottingham Law School, 2011 to 2012

Studied contract, trust, land, criminal, European Union, constitutional, tort, and employment law. Participated in negotiation competitions, mooting, and voluntary legal work.

## **Theology (Upper Second-Class Honours)**

University of Nottingham, 2008 to 2011

Submitted a dissertation on economic philosophy and theology. Attended and participated in various debates, committees, and conferences.

### Certifications

#### **Personal Alcohol Licence**

Nottingham City Council, 2013 to Present

#### First Aid at Work

St John Ambulance, 2021 to 2024

## Personal Projects

## github.com/elliotjreed/royal-mail-tracking

A PHP package for utilising the Royal Mail Shipping REST (v2) API.

#### github.com/elliotireed/haveibeenpwned

A PHP package for securely identifying leaked user email addresses and passwords.

## github.com/elliotjreed/www.elliotjreed.com

My personal website written in React 18 with server-side rendering via Express, with tests using React Testing Library with Jest.

#### github.com/elliotjreed/api.elliotjreed.com

A content API which returns structured data JSON from a Git repository, written in Symfony 6.1 with tests using PHPUnit.

#### github.com/elliotjreed/amp.elliotjreed.com

An AMP version of my website written in Go (Gin framework), Tailwind, and Docker.